indianweb2.com 2019-04-03

# Privacy Policy

## IndianWeb2.com Social Reader Privacy Policy

Indianweb2.com Social Reader is a free Facebook app that lets you easily share what you are reading and see what your friends are reading! In addition, the app uses the articles you read and those read by your friends to help personalize your experience.

This privacy policy describes what happens within the Social Reader app, but not what happens on Facebook outside of the app. In general, you are likely to be on Social Reader if you see the Social Reader logo in the top left corner.

If you do not see the Social Reader logo and you see the Facebook logo, it is likely that what you see is controlled by Facebook. [Click here](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ "Go to Facebook's privacy policy page") to view Facebook’s privacy policy for more detail on their practices.

### WHAT HAPPENS WHEN I READ AN ARTICLE IN THE SOCIAL READER APP?

When you authorize the Social Reader app, you may select who on Facebook can see the stories you post to Facebook. We look at your initial selection and apply it for your audience in the Social Reader app in a manner that is at least as protective of your privacy.

If you have set your Facebook audience for the Social Reader app to Friends or Public, activity within Social Reader (e.g., reading an article) may be shared for up to 30 days after that activity in the following ways:

  * Within the Social Reader app, we share your activity with your Facebook friends that also use the app when they are in the app.
  * Outside Facebook and the Social Reader app, we may present your activity to your Facebook friends on partner websites in widgets branded with Social Reader.

Alternatively, if you have set your Facebook audience for the Social Reader app to Only Me or Custom when you first authorize the app, activity within Social Reader will not be shared with others in the ways described above – that is, within the Social Reader app or on partner websites in websites branded with Social Reader.

Note: we’ll try to keep your preferences up to date, but if you change your Facebook settings after you first authorize the Social Reader app, your app setting changes may not be immediate.

We automatically share your Social Reader activity with Facebook. Facebook’s policies control how your Social Reader activity may be displayed on Facebook outside of the Social Reader app. See [below](https://www.indianweb2.com/privacy-policy#anchor_controlactivity "Jump to read about controlling activity display outside of Facebook") for more information.

### HOW CAN I HIDE THE FACT THAT I HAVE READ A PARTICULAR ARTICLE?

We understand that in some circumstances you may not want others to see what you are reading.You may delete publication of the fact that you have read an article. To do so, uncheck the checkmark in the sidebar of indianweb2.com.

By clicking the Remove from Your Reads button, the fact that you read the particular article will no longer be visible inside the Social Reader app or within a Social Reader widget on another website. It will also be deleted from within Facebook.

### CAN I DISABLE THE SOCIAL READER APP?

Yes, you can disable the Indianweb2.com Social Reader app by following the instructions [here.](https://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=170585223002660 "Read about Facebook privacy settings")

### HOW CAN I CONTROL HOW SOCIAL READER ACTIVITY IS DISPLAYED ON FACEBOOK OUTSIDE OF THE APP?

Your activity on the Social Reader app, such as the articles you read, is shared with Facebook. The display of Social Reader activity inside Facebook is handled solely by Facebook. If you would like to manage your activity within Facebook, including Social Reader activity, [click here](https://www.facebook.com/help/privacy "Go to Facebook's privacy policy page") to learn more. You can read more about Facebook’s privacy practices with respect to apps [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/how-apps-work "Go to Facebook's help page about how apps work") and [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/timeline/apps "Go to Facebook's help page about apps and the timeline").

### WHAT IS SOCIAL READER’S RELATIONSHIP WITH FACEBOOK?

Because Social Reader is an app within Facebook, information that you provide to us or that we collect could also be accessible to Facebook and is subject to Facebook’s privacy policy. Facebook may also collect other information about you in connection with your use of this app.

For more information on Facebook’s privacy practices, please [click here](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ "Go to Facebook's privacy policy page"), and for more information about Facebook’s privacy practices with respect to apps, please click [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/how-apps-work "Go to Facebook's help page about how apps work") and [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/timeline/apps "Go to Facebook's help page about apps and the timeline").

### WHAT HAPPENS WHEN I READ AN ARTICLE ON INDIANWEB2.COM

Articles you read on indianweb2.com or on the websites of any of our content partners will not automatically be shared with Facebook. To share articles while on content partner websites, click the Facebook Recommend button on an article-by-article basis.

### HOW DO I ASK QUESTIONS OR GIVE YOU FEEDBACK?

We want our privacy practices and choices to be as clear and helpful as possible. Tell us what you think by emailing us [here](https://www.indianweb2.com/contact-us/ "Go to our Contact Us page").

### WE WANTED TO COVER HOW INDIANWEBW2.COM SOCIAL READER WORKS FIRST; NOW HERE’S THE REST OF OUR PRIVACY POLICY.

IndianWeb2.com value your privacy. This Privacy Policy gives you information about our practices with respect to the personally identifiable information – information that could reasonably identify you – that we collect in connection with this app. Whenever you provide personally identifiable information to us, we will make an effort to link to our privacy policy.

### I. COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

We may ask you to provide personally identifiable information for various reasons and at various times. For example, when you sign up for the app, we may collect your email address, interests, and other information about your friends. We may ask for information about users at other times, too, such as when they contact us with a question. We may combine this information with other information (including personally identifiable information) about users that we may have collected from other sources.

We may automatically collect information about you when you use this app. For instance, we may automatically collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as which articles each user reads, which pages each user visits, where you click on this site, information about your specific interests and channels, the domain name, your IP address, Web browser software (such as Internet Explorer), and referring web site. In addition, we may place a “cookie” (a small, unique identifier text file) on your system to remember who you are. We also may include other information in our cookie files; for example, if you arrived at this site via a link from third-party site, we may include the URL of the linking page. You may opt out of the cookies delivered by us by changing the setting on your browser. Please be aware that this will disable all cookies delivered to your browser, not just the ones delivered by us. We may combine all of this information with other information, including personally identifiable information we have collected about you.

### II. USE OF INFORMATION

We use the information, including personally identifiable information that we have collected about you in several ways, including:

  * To manage and administer your account, including to process and fulfill the transactions you initiate, to identify you on the app, to send you information related to this app or various service providers, to solicit or respond to your questions or comments, to inform you of material changes or additions to this Privacy Policy or our terms and conditions, or to contact you with legal notices.
  * To send you offers and information from IndianWeb2.com and its affiliates or from other companies whose products and services may be of interest to you.
  * To provide you with a more personalized experience by serving you more relevant content and advertising.
  * To conduct research on our customers’ demographics, interests and behavior, to analyze traffic patterns, and generally for business analytics.
  * In other ways as described to you at the point of collection or otherwise.

### III. SHARING OF INFORMATION

We may share the information, including personally identifiable information that we collect about you in limited circumstances, including:

  * With respect to the articles you read, with your Facebook network, as described at the top of this Privacy Policy.
  * In aggregate form, with content partners of Indianweb2.com Social Reader.
  * With vendors providing contractual services for The Indianweb2.com (such as hosting vendors, list managers who facilitate or assist with communications on our behalf, companies that provide consulting or analytics services, and service providers who process payment information or transactions).
  * When we have reason to believe that disclosing this information may be necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms and Conditions or may be causing injury to or interference with the rights or property of Indianweb2.com or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities; to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or other government agency; and when we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or otherwise required by law.
  * In the event that our ownership changes as a result of a merger, acquisition, or corporate transfer to another company.
  * With a service provider with your permission (e.g., if you sign up as a lead).
  * If you give us permission, with selected third parties for their direct marketing purposes.
  * With other entities for business analytics.
  * In other ways as described to you at the point of collection or otherwise.

### IV. ACCESS TO INFORMATION

You can access and update personally identifiable information that you have provided to us via Facebook’s [privacy settings page](http://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=privacy&section=apps&h=936766c538f73427c9eecc29d9a78f94 "Go to Facebook's privacy settings page"). You can access and update any personally identifiable information that you have provided directly to us, or ask us questions, by contacting us [here](https://www.indianweb2.com/contact-us/ "Contact us").

### V. DATA SECURITY

We have in place administrative, technical, and physical measures to protect the information we collect online. However, we cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

### VI. EXTERNAL LINKS

Many parts of this website link you to other news websites. Please note that those websites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, disclosing, and protecting personal information.

### VII. PERSONS UNDER AGE 13

In general, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from individuals under the age of 13. Please do not send any information about yourself to us if you are under the age of 13. Should we learn that a person under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete that information from our database.

### VIII. MATERIAL CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

If we need to materially change this Privacy Policy in the future, we will notify you by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account or by placing a prominent notice on this app. Please note that you are responsible for updating your information so that we have your current email address, and for checking the website and Privacy Policy periodically for notice of changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of personally identifiable information provided to us prior to our notification to you of the changes. Therefore, if you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your information, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to terminate your account with us.

### IX. CONTACTING US

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.indianweb2.com/contact-us/ "Contact us").
